Erich Keil

Developer, Collaborator, Problem Solver.

Tulsa, OK

erich@zenlex.dev

773-580-1595

Portfolio:

zenlex.dev

Github:

github.com/zenlex

<u>LinkedIn</u>:

zenlexltd

Objective:

To apply my passion for problem solving to build tools that make the world a better place for all who live in it. I have a broad set of skills in software, hardware, media generation, and design. I also have significant experience in managing complex projects in highly variable environments and bring a strong history of collaboration and intrinsically motivated learning. I strive to support the continued development of clients and colleagues.

Code Skills:

- JavaScript/Node.js
- HTML5
- CSS
- React
- Git/GitHub
- SQL/Postgres
- MongoDB
- RESTful APIs
- GraphQL

Experience:

Participant

Recurse Center, NYC, Jan 2022 to Mar 2022 Developed and collaborated on a broad spectrum of projects and learning activities including:

- Generative art with Three.js, p5.js, and CSS
- · Daily algorithms & data structures study
- · Regular pair programming
- Full Stack Web App Development.

Design Skills:

- Lighting Design
- Sound Design
- Photography
- Figma
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Audition

Director of Production

Tulsa Opera, Tulsa, OK, Aug 2017 to Dec 2021

- Planned and implemented a \$1.5M annual production budget.
- Oversaw all design and technical elements.
- Hired and managed technicians, designers, and stage managers.
- Designed and implemented health and safety protocols, season selection & scheduling processes, and long range strategic planning.
- Served as chief technical liaison for a \$6M construction project.

Related Skills:

- -Public Speaking
- -Teaching
- -Curriculum

Development

- -Research
- -Strategic Planning
- -Electrical Theory
- -Embedded Hardware

Education

MFA:

Theater Design and Technology University of California-Los Angeles

BA:

Theater Design and Technology Western Michigan University

Memberships:

- -Techlahoma
- -Code for Tulsa

Associate Professor -Lighting and Sound Design

East Carolina University - Aug 2011 to Jul 2017

- Designed and taught core and advanced courses in lighting and sound design and technology for live performance.
- Designed or mentored student designers and oversaw implementation of Lighting and Sound elements for the ECU/Loessin Playhouse.
- Served as Design & Production area coordinator, managing curriculum development and educational operations within the Design & Production concentration.
- Served as Production Manager overseeing calendar and budget coordination for the department's production activities.

Asst. Professor - Theater - Production Bradley University Sep 2005 to Jul 2011

- Designed and taught courses in Lighting and Sound Design and Technology, Scenic Design and Stagecraft.
- Managed scenery, lighting, and AV shops.
- Designed production elements and mentored student designers and technicians.
- Collaborated on strategic planning, budget design and oversight, curriculum development, and accreditation processes.

Talks/Presentations:

"Skill Transfer as a Learning Model: A Case Study in Joining the Circus" - OKC Web Devs/FCCOK - *February 2022*

References Available Upon Request

Ken McConnell General Director/CEO Tulsa Opera, Inc. kmcconnell@tulsaopera.com parkerth@ecu.edu 918-582-4035x106

Reid Parker Technical Director East Carolina Univ. 252-328-6925

Charlene Gross Costume Designer Production Manager charlene.gross@gmail.com 347-524-6788